<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temple Real Estate Video Blog with Ryan Smith</title>
    <description>Our mission at Ryan Smith Home Selling Team is to be your best resource for Temple real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Ryan Smith Home Selling Team, your professional Temple Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 15:27:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 15:27:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Part 2: 6 Buying &amp; Selling Mistakes to Avoid</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zdE-C2_85xQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are six mistakes you want to avoid during a simultaneous sale. Here are the last three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final episode of our two-part series about the biggest mistakes to avoid when buying and selling at the same time, we’ll go over the final three pitfalls that can harm your simultaneous transactions. To recap the first part of this series, click here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are the final three mistakes to avoid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Working with too little of a cushion when it comes to financing and terms.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re selling your house for a certain number because you absolutely need that amount to purchase your next home, you’re not leaving yourself that much cushion. You never know what will happen during negotiations. You don’t know what a buyer will ask for, and cutting it tight can make the situation way more stressful. Try to have a little bit of a cushion in terms of what you need from your sale and what you require for your next purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=TRY TO HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF A CUSHION IN TERMS OF WHAT YOU NEED FROM YOUR SALE AND WHAT YOU REQUIRE FOR YOUR NEXT PURCHASE.%20http://localhost:4000/part-2-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“TRY TO HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF A CUSHION IN TERMS OF WHAT YOU NEED FROM YOUR SALE AND WHAT YOU REQUIRE FOR YOUR NEXT PURCHASE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Failing to compromise.&lt;/strong&gt; When going through the buying or selling process, it’s easy to stand on principle and refuse to compromise on what you want or what you’re willing to do. There’s a time and a place to put your foot down, but during a real estate transaction, you should think long and hard on whether little things like not wanting to fix a broken window are worth potentially putting a stop to the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Using two different real estate agents.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re moving out of town after you sell your current home, then using two different agents is a way better idea than using just one, but if you’re buying and selling in the same area, the process will be a lot smoother if you use just one agent or team. On our team, for example, we have specialized agents who focus on just one side of the transaction, so if you worked with us, you’d get the best of both worlds in terms of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, if you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/part-2-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/part-2-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Part 1: 6 Buying &amp; Selling Mistakes to Avoid</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AmxKWZc7dX4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are six mistakes you want to avoid during a simultaneous sale. Here are the first three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part one of our two-part series on real estate mistakes, we’ll be going over the first three pitfalls you want to avoid when buying and selling at the same time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Waiting too long to prepare your home for the market.&lt;/strong&gt; If you wait until the last second to prepare your home, it can cause a lot of unnecessary stress. You may have to paint walls, repair decks, and more. Don’t wait until it’s too late!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Not having a backup plan.&lt;/strong&gt; When you’re going through the buying and selling processes at the same time, there are a lot of moving parts to consider. It’s good to have something to fall back on if issues come up and you need to make changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T LET REALITY HIT YOU AFTER YOU’VE FOUND THE PERFECT HOME.%20http://localhost:4000/part-1-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T LET REALITY HIT YOU AFTER YOU’VE FOUND THE PERFECT HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not speaking with a lender before starting the home search.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t talk with a lender up front, you won’t have a pre-qualification or pre-approval and you’ll have no idea what you can actually afford. Don’t let reality hit you after you’ve found the perfect home; speaking with a lender from the outset will help eliminate the daydreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for part two of our series, where we’ll cover the final three mistakes to avoid during a simultaneous sale. If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/part-1-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/part-1-6-buying-selling-mistakes-to.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Long Does a Pre-Approval Last?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iqqdX3GGzBU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get pre-approved, how long is this pre-approval good for? Find out with today’s quick message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably already understand the importance of getting pre-approved. After all, meeting with a lender to verify your capacity to buy is the first step you should take in your home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after a lender reviews the necessary documents (bank statements, pay stubs, etc.) and explains what kind of home you can afford, how long will this pre-approval last?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MEETING WITH A LENDER TO VERIFY YOUR CAPACITY TO BUY IS THE FIRST STEP YOU SHOULD TAKE IN YOUR HOME SEARCH.%20http://localhost:4000/how-long-does-pre-approval-last.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MEETING WITH A LENDER TO VERIFY YOUR CAPACITY TO BUY IS THE FIRST STEP YOU SHOULD TAKE IN YOUR HOME SEARCH.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, you’ve got quite some time before your mortgage pre-approval will expire. Lenders understand that buying a home can be intense. They know it can’t happen overnight, so most mortgage pre-approvals will remain valid for at least 90 days. After that point, you may need to undergo a second pre-approval process to ensure that you still have the means to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-long-does-pre-approval-last.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-long-does-pre-approval-last.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Sell Your Home This Year</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TH5l2gBj7no?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you sell your home in 2019? Absolutely, and here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home prices have been on a meteoric rise for years, inventory is incredibly low, and the market continues to favor sellers. If you haven’t thought about it already, here are five reasons why you should sell your home this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When there is little inventory, there is little competition.&lt;/strong&gt; If you list now, you may be the only listed home in your area, which means you’ll get much more attention. Inventory is beginning to increase, however, so you’ll see more competition over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. In a seller’s market, you tend to make more of a profit.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve seen home values increase dramatically over the last few years. This is beginning to slow down, however, and waiting to sell doesn’t guarantee you’ll make more down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=INVENTORY IS INCREDIBLY LOW, AND THE MARKET CONTINUES TO FAVOR SELLERS.%20http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-sell-your-home-this-year.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“INVENTORY IS INCREDIBLY LOW, AND THE MARKET CONTINUES TO FAVOR SELLERS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. There is a high demand for homes under $300,000.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re in the entry-level price point, you’ll enjoy a lot of attention from first-time homebuyers. The price range between $150,000 and $225,000 has a high demand for homes and a low inventory, allowing you to really capitalize on your sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Mortgage rates are low.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re at a 12-month low of around 4.25%, and this contributes a lot to buyer demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. There are a lot of millennials entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt; People tend to buy their first home around the age of 30. Since many will reach this age within the next two years, it means there will be many new buyers in the market, which will push price and demand upward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to get your home on the market or wanting to learn more, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-sell-your-home-this-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-sell-your-home-this-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Trust Zillows Zestimates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_mtNIfPhC0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zestimates aren’t always accurate when it comes to determining a home’s value. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we’re working with buyers or sellers, the subject of Zillow’s Zestimates comes up quite often, and the No. 1 question we usually get asked about them is, “Are they accurate?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s review what a Zestimate is. Basically, it’s Zillow’s home valuation tool that’s based on a computer-generated algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately (or fortunately, depending on your situation), Zestimates aren’t always accurate. If you’re a home seller and you live in a cookie-cutter neighborhood where all the homes are the same, your Zestimate has a better chance of being accurate. If you don’t live in a cookie-cutter neighborhood, though, Zillow will have a hard time giving your home an accurate Zestimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU WANT TO GET A TRULY ACCURATE VALUATION OF YOUR HOME, THE BEST THING YOU CAN DO IS CONTACT A REAL ESTATE AGENT SUCH AS MYSELF.%20http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU WANT TO GET A TRULY ACCURATE VALUATION OF YOUR HOME, THE BEST THING YOU CAN DO IS CONTACT A REAL ESTATE AGENT SUCH AS MYSELF.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? A Zestimate can’t account for any upgrades you’ve made to your house. If you’ve installed brand-new granite countertops, redone your flooring, or repainted the entire house, that added value won’t be reflected in your home’s Zestimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get a truly accurate valuation of your home, the best thing you can do is contact a real estate agent such as myself so we can visit the property in person and consult with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds like something you’d be interested in or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 11:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Forget to Do These Things When You Move</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/699TjCihiVA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to forget a lot of things when they’re moving. Here are five such items that you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re moving into a new home, there’s a lot of stress involved. With that being the case, homeowners tend to forget about certain things during the process. Here is a list of the top five things you should remember when moving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Switch banks.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are at a regional bank and moving to a different region, you’ll need to switch banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Take care of medical needs.&lt;/strong&gt; You might have to get a new doctor, too. This is another thing that can fall by the wayside during the moving process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Transfer your utilities.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes things like cable, utilities, and internet. Make sure your utilities are turned off at your old home and on at your new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=TRY TO BE AWARE OF TRANSFER EXPENSES UP FRONT AND BUDGET THEM INTO YOUR MOVING COSTS.%20http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-to-do-these-things-when-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“TRY TO BE AWARE OF TRANSFER EXPENSES UP FRONT AND BUDGET THEM INTO YOUR MOVING COSTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prepare for transfer fees.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if you have a home alarm contract, you might have to pay a fee or penalty for canceling your agreement early. Try to be aware of any expenses upfront and budget them into your moving costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Raid the kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t leave any food behind. The freezer is a common place where these items end up sitting for years until you move. One great idea is to take inventory of what’s in your freezer and start planning to cook it before the move happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are five basic things that you should keep an eye on if you’re considering a move. If you have any questions in the meantime or if you are interested in buying or selling a home in the area anytime soon, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 11:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-to-do-these-things-when-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-to-do-these-things-when-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Surviving a Sellers Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here to discuss four very important tips for surviving a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our market has been fairly competitive, so here are four tips that we’ve compiled to help buyers compete more favorably in a tough market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Submit a large earnest money deposit.&lt;/strong&gt; Earnest money is like a deposit you can put down with your contract. The great thing about earnest money is that as long as you adhere to the contract, that money is never at risk. If for some reason an inspection turns out badly or things don’t otherwise work out, there are ways you can back out of that contract. The larger the deposit you put down, the more attractive it makes you look to a seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Make sure you’re pre-qualified.&lt;/strong&gt; This is extremely important; listing agents looking over offers want to see that you’ve been pre-qualified with a reputable local lender. A pre-qualification letter will show the seller of the property that you’re serious and qualified to move forward with the transaction. If the lender you’re pre-qualified with is local and reputable, it will always carry more weight in the seller’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A PRE-QUALIFICATION LETTER WILL SHOW THE SELLER OF THE PROPERTY THAT YOU’RE SERIOUS AND QUALIFIED TO MOVE FORWARD WITH THE TRANSACTION.%20http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-surviving-sellers-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A PRE-QUALIFICATION LETTER WILL SHOW THE SELLER OF THE PROPERTY THAT YOU’RE SERIOUS AND QUALIFIED TO MOVE FORWARD WITH THE TRANSACTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Give the seller time to move.&lt;/strong&gt; Once their home has been sold, a seller will need time to pack their things together, coordinate their families, and move out. If you don’t give them a lot of time to pack up, that will create a very stressful experience for them. If you include a lenient move-out time in your original offer, it might be a way to further incentivize the seller to choose your offer over others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Write your best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; There have been a number of times when I’ve worked as a listing agent to evaluate different offers on my seller’s home that I’ve seen a family who really, really wants the house for any number of reasons, but they’ll come up $500 or $1,000 short on their offer. If you consider this over the next 15 to 30 years, that $1,000 means absolutely nothing; it will make almost no dent in your monthly payment. I hate to see people miss out on getting a house that they love over $4 a month. Always put your best and strongest offer forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying or selling a house, feel free to visit our website at www.RyanSmithHomes.com, or else contact us at any time. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-surviving-sellers-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-surviving-sellers-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Final 5 Common Real Estate Myths</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B-ZmmbFCNkA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’ll discuss part two of the top 10 common myths in real estate and debunk our final five misconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’ll be sharing the second part of my two-part series on the top 10 myths in real estate, featuring myths No. 6 through No. 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Weekends bring out the most serious buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; When people are preparing to put their house on the market, we often hear of sellers thinking they won’t be able to show it during the week, so they make showings available for the weekend only. Serious homebuyers, however, are coming throughout the week, and while you are more likely to have showings on the weekends because people are off, you may still get buyers during the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Zillow says it, therefore it is right.&lt;/strong&gt; First, I want to say that Zillow is very rarely accurate. There is nothing more frustrating as a real estate agent than having folks come in and say that Zillow says the home is worth a certain amount. While you can get good information from these types of websites, they are very rarely accurate because they use algorithms based on tax records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EVERY SELLER IS IN A DIFFERENT SITUATION AND HAS DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES INVOLVING THEIR SALE.%20http://localhost:4000/the-final-5-common-real-estate-myths.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EVERY SELLER IS IN A DIFFERENT SITUATION AND HAS DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES INVOLVING THEIR SALE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. It is better to initially list a home on the high side because you can always negotiate it down.&lt;/strong&gt; If you start out too high, it is actually one of the fastest ways to kill your home sale. When you initially list your home, you’ll have the most activity that you are going to have; if the price is too high, you end up missing out on people. If you try to make adjustments and catch up later, those people have already moved on to other properties and your momentum that you need to sell for top dollar is gone. Although I actually love pricing homes as the highest in the neighborhood, it has to be priced realistically so you can get the most money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Multiple price reductions mean that a seller is desperate to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; Every seller is in a different situation and has different circumstances involved in their sale. This does not necessarily mean that someone is desperate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. All agents are the same and do the same exact thing.&lt;/strong&gt; This is definitely not true. If you look at the results, you can see very different outcomes depending on the team or person you hire. The people who are successful or have been successful for a long period of time are clearly doing things differently to enable them to achieve that kind of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 16:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-final-5-common-real-estate-myths.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-final-5-common-real-estate-myths.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 10 Myths About Real Estate, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NNYTLTYCGBk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 10 major real estate myths you shouldn’t buy into, and here are the first five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five of the top 10 most common real estate myths floating around out there and the truth behind them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The agent keeps all of the commission.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve heard this one many times over the years. As an agent myself, I wish it was true, but it’s not. When we list a home for one of our clients, our team typically spends thousands of dollars marketing and advertising it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Agents typically charge a 6% commission rate.&lt;/strong&gt; The truth is, there is no standard commission cost among agents. Some charge 6%, some charge more, and some charge less. What kind of commission rate an agent charges should reflect the value that they bring to you. If an agent can sell your home quickly and sell it for thousands of dollars more than the average agent can, they’ll probably be worth more and cost more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Agents can get reimbursed for car-related expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; When agents are out showing houses, they have to pay their own transportation expenses. However, some of these expenses can be deducted from their taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WHAT KIND OF COMMISSION RATE AN AGENT CHARGES SHOULD REFLECT THE VALUE THAT THEY BRING TO YOU.%20http://localhost:4000/the-top-10-myths-about-real-estate-part.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WHAT KIND OF COMMISSION RATE AN AGENT CHARGES SHOULD REFLECT THE VALUE THAT THEY BRING TO YOU.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Agents can be reimbursed for marketing expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate companies, even the large ones like RE/MAX or Keller Williams, don’t dictate to their agents how they should market their homes. This is why, even at big-name brands, you’ll see both agents who are very successful and agents who aren’t. Because they don’t mandate any form of marketing, its up to the agent what they want to spend on marketing their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A home either “passes” or “fails” an inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; The purpose of a home inspection is to point out any issues that a home may have. Any home will have its share of deficiencies, and just because there are issues revealed in the inspection doesn’t mean it “passes” or “fails.” If anything, these deficiencies enable the buyer and seller to negotiate over the home’s condition and its price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the second part of this series, where we’ll delve into some myths that are more related to the real estate sales process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-10-myths-about-real-estate-part.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-top-10-myths-about-real-estate-part.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Pros and Cons of Open Houses</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0jku7ZEoe8c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m often asked whether open houses help sell homes. Today, I will be sharing the pros and cons of this strategy so you can decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/buy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryansmithhomes.com/sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Value Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do open houses work or not? Depending on the agent that you talk to, you are going to hear a lot of different opinions. For this reason, I thought it would be a good idea to discuss some pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with our list of cons. First, open houses provide a very low probability of a sale. This might sound pessimistic, but it’s important to understand the true odds of successfully finding a buyer from hosting an open house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, there are a lot of security concerns involved. With so many potential buyers touring your home at once, it can be difficult to keep an eye on everyone. And, although I have never personally encountered such an issue, open houses can invite the potential for theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to keep track of all of them is very difficult and it is very possible that someone gets into your stuff and steals something. Although I have never personally had this issue at any of my open houses or showings, it’s not unheard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third drawback of hosting an open house is that it could bring out nosy neighbors. Oftentimes, the majority of people who turn out for an open house are from your own neighborhood. Rather than showing up with an interest in buying your home, they attend simply out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OPEN HOUSES CAN INVITE THE POTENTIAL FOR THEFT.%20http://localhost:4000/the-pros-and-cons-of-open-houses.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OPEN HOUSES CAN INVITE THE POTENTIAL FOR THEFT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a positive note, an open house is, well,  open to everybody. Anyone can drive up and walk through the house, which sometimes pulls down the barriers to engaging with a real estate agent. While it is rare that these people end up buying the house that you are selling, it does allow you potentially pick up a buyer. Agents can engage with these people and discuss what they are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open houses also offer a lot of convenience. They allow potential buyers to see your property without scheduling a showing.  The final benefit I’d like to highlight is that open houses provide buyers with a more complete perspective on your home. It’s one thing to see a home in photos, videos, or in a 3D virtual walkthrough, but it’s something else entirely to actually visit it in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do open houses work? It depends on your goals. Open houses offer a great networking opportunity, especially for agents, but the odds of finding a buyer at such an event is lower than some may assume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 14:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-pros-and-cons-of-open-houses.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-pros-and-cons-of-open-houses.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
